loopt.com 2011-11-09

# Loopt

Privacy Notice

Loopt, Inc. (" _Loopt_ ") values the privacy of our customers (collectively or individually, " _Users_ ") who use the mobile applications, www.loopt.com Web site, and other web sites, online services, or content (e.g., widgets, feeds, and applications) owned or operated by Loopt (collectively, the " _Loopt Services_ "). 

This Privacy Notice governs the Loopt Services, and details important information about the use and disclosure of User information collected through the Loopt Services. Loopt provides this Privacy Notice to help you make an informed decision about whether to use the Loopt Services.

**This Privacy Notice is incorporated into and is subject to theLoopt Terms of Service. Your use of the Loopt Services and any personal information you provide on the Loopt Services remains subject to the terms of this Privacy Notice and the Terms of Service. **

**IMPORTANT DISCLOSURES AND CONSENTS:**

  * **Unlimited Data and messaging plans are recommended for the Loopt Services. For some services, Loopt requires the use of SMS text messages. Standard data and messaging charges and taxes from your carrier apply.**
  * **Loopt collects, maintains, uses, and displays your personal data and the geographic location of your mobile device (we call this location fix of your device "location information" or "geo-location") to provide the Loopt Services.**
  * **By using the Loopt Services, you have consented to: (1) the use of your device's location to provide Loopt's services including relevant advertisements, and the display of that location information to your Loopt friends and within your geo-tagged messages and content; (2) receive text messages and emails; and (3) pay carrier data, messaging, and other fees resulting from Loopt usage.**
  * **The Loopt Services default privacy settings are set for the way that most Users use the services: we save your password for the mobile applications, your mobile device's geo-location is updated automatically, and that location information may be displayed to your Loopt friends even when Loopt is not open and running on your device. Changing these settings is easy - just select 'Settings' on the Loopt mobile application or manage your preferences via the Loopt.com Web site.**
  * **Please note that any personal information you voluntarily disclose online becomes publicly available and can be read, collected, and used by others and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. Loopt is not responsible for the information that you choose to disclose publicly on or through the Loopt Services.**

THE INFORMATION LOOPT COLLECTS:

  * **"REGISTRATION INFORMATION"** : You provide certain personally-identifiable information (such as mobile phone number, wireless carrier / operator, your name, email address, phone number, date of birth, password, etc.) when subscribing to the Loopt Services. 
  * **"PROFILE INFORMATION"** : When using the Loopt Services you provide certain other personal information and content - such as event times and locations, interests and hobbies, age, gender, sexual orientation, relationship status, and favorite places for breakfast, drinks, dancing, outdoor activities, etc. - that will be publicly displayed to other Users and on third-party sites and services (for example, when using the Loopt Services to publish updates to Twitter, Facebook, etc.) in accordance with your privacy settings. 
  * **"LOCATION INFORMATION"** : To provide the Loopt Services, we derive location information from your wireless carrier, certain third-party service providers, or directly from the mobile device that you used to register. This location tracking of your mobile device may occur even when the Loopt mobile applications are not actively open and running in the foreground, but your location is displayed and shared with others only in accordance with your privacy settings. 
  * **"COOKIES, PERSISTENT FILE INFORMATION"** : When you use the Loopt Services, we may send one or more cookies (small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters) to your computer. Loopt may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie disappears after you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains after you close your web browser and may be used by us during your subsequent visits to the Loopt Web site. Persistent cookies set by the Loopt Web site can be removed. Please review your web browser "Help" file to learn the proper way to modify your cookie settings. 
  * **"LOG FILE INFORMATION"** : When you use the Loopt Services, our servers automatically record certain information about your usage. These server logs may include information such as a mobile device identification number and device identifier, web requests, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser language, referring / exit pages and URLs, platform type, number of clicks, domain names, search terms, ratings, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, features used in the Loopt mobile applications, the number of messages and friend requests related to your profile, the amount of time spent on particular screens, the dates and times of your requests, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. 
  * **"INVITE-A-FRIEND INFORMATION"** : If you choose to use our invite-a-friend feature, then Loopt will ask you for your friend's mobile phone number or email address. If you provide a friend's mobile phone number, then Loopt will automatically send to that friend a one-time text message inviting your friend to join the Loopt Service and to add you as their friend. If your friend's phone number is on a wireless provider or mobile device that is not supported, then your friend will not receive this text message until their wireless provider or mobile device supports the Loopt Services. If you provide a friend's email address, then Loopt will automatically send that friend a one-time email inviting your friend to register on the Loopt website. **Your friend may contact Loopt at[privacy@loopt.com](mailto:privacy@loopt.com) to request that Loopt remove this information from our systems, or simply reply with STOP to any Loopt friend-invitation text message to opt-out of receiving future invitations via text message. **

THE WAY LOOPT USES INFORMATION:

  * Loopt uses your personally identifiable, registration, profile, and location information to operate, maintain, and provide to you and other Users all of the features and functionality of the Loopt Services. 
  * To provide the basic functionality of the Loopt Services - such as displaying your live location to Loopt friends on the Friends Map or alerting your friends when you are nearby - Loopt maintains for its use only each User's most recent location fix. If Users choose to "geo-tag" certain content or data with location information, then Loopt maintains these geo-tags for so long as the applicable content remains on Loopt's systems. 
  * Loopt uses your personally identifiable, location, and certain non-personally-identifiable information (such as anonymous log file information) to track and analyze User preferences and trends in order to improve the quality and design of the Loopt Services and to create new features, promotions, functionality, and services.
  * Loopt uses cookies and log file information to: (a) remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Loopt Services; (b) provide custom and personalized content, advertisements, and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns; and (d) monitor aggregate usage metrics.
  * Loopt uses a third-party data source to verify that your mobile phone number is on a wireless provider supported by Loopt. If you have a supported mobile phone number and device, then Loopt sends a text message to your phone in order to verify your custody of that handset. If your carrier or handset is not supported, then Loopt stores your mobile phone number and will send a one-time text message to you when the Loopt Service does become available on your wireless provider or handset.
  * Loopt uses your email address or mobile number from time-to-time to send you messages from Loopt such as privacy or security related notices, notifying you of major Loopt Services updates, or for other customer service purposes.
  * Loopt uses your personally identifiable, registration, profile, and location information to serve and personalize in-service advertisements specifically tailored to you and your interests. For example, if you put a favorite band in your profile, then we might serve you an advertisement highlighting the concert of a similar band playing nearby in your city. However, we do not disclose who you are to the music company or advertiser.
  * _Loopt does not use your personally identifiable information or location information to send commercial SMS text messages to you without your express consent or unless if you have opted-in to be part of a specific program or feature in accordance with the applicable Loopt Services consent procedures._

WHEN LOOPT DISCLOSES INFORMATION:

  * Loopt discloses some personally identifiable, registration, profile, or location information to subsidiaries, affiliated companies, or other businesses or persons to: (a) provide certain features; (b) serve relevant advertisements in support of the Loopt Services; and (c) process such information on our behalf. For example, we may disclose information to wireless carrier partners for the purpose of revenue recognition, or we may disclose certain information in order to provide mapping, points-of-interest, local content, or navigation features. We require that these parties agree to process such information in compliance with this Privacy Notice and use appropriate confidentiality and security measures, and we use reasonable efforts to limit their use of such information.
  * Loopt discloses aggregate, anonymous log file and usage information in reports to interested third parties to assist those parties in understanding the usage patterns and perfomance results of certain advertisements, content, services, promotions, or features. For example, we may provide aggregate-level reports to an advertising partner for the purpose of showing delivery and performance statistics of a specific advertising campaign.
  * Loopt may release personally identifiable, registration, profile, or location information if required to do so by law, or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with state and federal laws or respond to a court order, subpoena, or search warrant.
  * Loopt also reserves the right to disclose personally identifiable, registration, profile, or location information that Loopt believes, in good faith, is appropriate or necessary to: enforce our Terms of Service; take precautions against liability; protect Users from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; investigate and defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations; assist government enforcement agencies; protect the security or integrity of the Loopt Services; or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Loopt, Users, or others. 
  * _Loopt does not disclose your personally identifiable information or location information connected to your personally identifiable information to other companies for their commercial use without your express consent or unless you have opted-in to be part of a specific program or feature in accordance with the applicable Loopt Services consent procedures._

YOUR CHOICES: 

You may update, correct, or delete your privacy settings and profile information at any time. To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you profile access or making corrections. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times.

OUR COMMITMENT TO DATA SECURITY:

Loopt uses commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information that Loopt receives on your behalf to operate the Loopt Services or that you transmit to Loopt and you do so at your own risk. We also cannot guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

If Loopt learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. Loopt may post a notice on the Loopt Services if a security breach occurs. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing.

OUR COMMITMENT TO CHILDREN'S PRIVACY:

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, Loopt does not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information on the Loopt Services from persons under 14 years-of-age, and no part of Loopt Services is directed to persons under 14. IF YOU ARE UNDER 14 YEARS OF AGE, THEN PLEASE DO NOT USE OR ACCESS THE LOOPT SERVICES AT ANY TIME OR IN ANY MANNER. If Loopt learns that personally-identifiable information of persons less than 14-years-of-age has been collected on the Loopt Services without verifiable parental consent, then Loopt will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 14 has obtained a Loopt Services account, then you may alert Loopt at [privacy@loopt.com](mailto:privacy@loopt.com) and request that Loopt delete that child's personal information from our systems. 

Parents, the following are some resources that may help you in understanding and guiding your children's access to the Internet. While Loopt does not endorse these sites or products, we provide the following information as a public service to our Users.

  * **OnGuard Online** ( _maintained by Federal Trade Commission_ ) <http://onguardonline.gov/socialnetworking.html>
  * **ConnectSafely.org** : [http://www.connectsafely.org](http://www.connectsafely.org/)
  * **SafeKids.com** : [http://safekids.com](http://safekids.com/)
  * **NetFamilyNews.org** : [http://www.netfamilynews.org](http://www.netfamilynews.org/)
  * **WebWiseKids.org** : [http://www.webwisekids.org](http://www.webwisekids.org/)
  * **Center for Safe and Responsible Internet Use** : [http://www.csriu.org](http://www.csriu.org/)
  * **GetNetWise.org** : [http://getnetwise.org](http://getnetwise.org/)

INTERNATIONAL VISITORS:

The Loopt Services are hosted in the United States and are intended for United States visitors. If you are using the Loopt Services from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, then please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States and by providing your personal data you consent to that transfer.

THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISERS AND AD-SERVING COMPANIES:

Advertisements that appear on the Loopt Services are sometimes delivered (or "served") directly to Users by third-party advertisers or ad network companies. These companies may automatically receive your IP address or other information about your mobile device or personal computer when serving advertisements. These third parties may also download cookies to your computer, or use other technologies such as JavaScript and "web beacons" (also known as "1x1 gifs") to measure the effectiveness of the advertisements served and to personalize advertising content. Doing this allows the advertiser or ad network to recognize your computer or mobile device each time they send you an advertisement in order to measure the effectiveness of the ad and to personalize advertising content. These companies may compile information about the sites or services visited when seeing advertisements and determine which advertisements are clicked. Loopt does not access or have control of the cookies that may be placed by third-party advertisers or ad networks. Likewise, third party advertisers and ad networks do not have access to your personal information stored with Loopt unless you choose to share it with them. **This Privacy Notice does not cover the use of tracking technologies or personal data by any such third-party advertisers or ad networks.**

IN THE EVENT OF MERGER, SALE, OR BANKRUPTCY:

In the event that Loopt is acquired by or merged with a third party entity, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information we have collected from our Users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control so that the Loopt Services can continue operations. In the unlikely event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, we may not be able to control how your personal information is treated, transferred, or used.

CHANGES AND UPDATES TO THIS PRIVACY NOTICE:

This Privacy Notice may be revised periodically without further notice to you and this will be reflected by the "last modified" notice below. Please revisit this page to stay aware of any changes. In general, we only use your personal information in the manner described in the Privacy Notice in effect when we received that personal information. Your continued use of the Loopt Services constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Notice and any future revisions. If we decide to change our privacy policies, then we will post those changes to this Privacy Notice, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

For revisions to this Privacy Notice that may be materially less restrictive on our use or disclosure of personal information you have provided to us, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you and obtain your consent before implementing such revisions with respect to such information. If we make such material changes to this policy, then we will notify you here in this Privacy Notice, by email, or by means of a notice on the Loopt Services home page.

EFFECTIVE DATE, DATE LAST MODIFIED:

Loopt Privacy Notice effective as of September 5, 2006.

Loopt Privacy Notice last modified on October 15, 2009.

CONTACT INFORMATION:

Loopt, Inc. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the Loopt Services. Because Loopt wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact our Privacy Manager at [privacy@loopt.com](mailto:privacy@loopt.com). If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at _http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php_ . TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns. 

PLEASE CONTACT OUR PRIVACY MANAGER AT [privacy@loopt.com](mailto:privacy@loopt.com) OR BY POSTAL MAIL AT LOOPT, INC., 590 W. EL CAMINO REAL, MOUNTAIN VIEW, CA 94040 WITH ANY QUESTIONS OR COMMENTS ABOUT THIS PRIVACY NOTICE. WE WILL RESPOND TO YOUR INQUIRY WITHIN 30 DAYS OF ITS RECEIPT.
